JIALI DUAN

+1(213) 204-0380 \diamond Mountain View, CA jli.duan@gmail.com \diamond Linkedin \diamond Website

SUMMARY

I am a researcher with a strong track record in Computer Vision and Artificial Intelligence. I am particularly interested in multi-modality learning, foundation models, and generative AI. I am a quick learner and have a broad interest in new researches and technologies. I have experience in a variety of research projects, including self-supervised learning, vision-language pretraining, and human-robot interaction. I am also proficient in a variety of research tools, including Pytorch3d, Detectron2, Mujoco, Blender, Unity ML, Colmap, Opengl etc.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2021 PhD in Electrical and Computer Engineering

University of Southern California

2014 - 2017 MSc in Computer Science

Chinese Academy of Sciences

2010 - 2014 BS in Information Engineering

East China University of Science and Technology

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Scientist

Jun. 2022 - Present

FAIR Labs, Meta AI

Menlo Park, CA

- Contributed to data-scaling and model-scaling efforts of **Text-to-4D** by building a blender-based rendering pipeline and a structure-from-motion (SfM) based reconstruction pipeline. Explored a 3D counterpart of Segment-Anything model for learning category-agnostic 3D reconstruction priors.
- Re-implemented a customized **NeRF** library with reusable research components for 3D volumetric rendering and acceleration.
- Prototyped a diffusion-inspired vision-language grounding framework for foundational pretraining.
- Diff reviewer and Contributor for Pytorch3d v0.7.1 and v0.7.2. Examples include Cuda/C++/python kernels for Marching Cubes, glTF utilities, and Fisheye Camera components.
- Lead the 3D data crowd-sourcing efforts by deploying Amazon Mturk websites and building the structure-frommotion stack including hloc, colmap integration, 3D animation and selection criteria metrics.

Applied Scientist II

June. 2021 - Jun. 2022

M5 Core Modeling, Search Science AI, Amazon

Palo Alto, CA

- Performed large multi-modal pretraining for generic object embeddings that serve a variety of downstream services at Amazon including product search, click-through-rate (CTR) and improving multi-lingual, multi-task metrics.
- Contributed to the LLM infra stack by customizing and diving into open-source frameworks such as DeepSpeed, Hugging Face and Timm.
- Mentored two interns and published 1 NeurIPS, 2 CVPR papers on multi-modal representation learning.

Applied Scientist Intern

Summer of 2019, 2020, 2021

A9, Amazon

Palo Alto, CA

- Developed one of the earliest semi-supervised metric learning frameworks for leveraging both labeled and unlabeled data in teacher-student distillation that achieved SOTA in retrieval tasks.
- Published 1 CVPR paper on SSL and 1 SCMLS paper on fashion compatibility recommendation with graph.

Research Intern

April. 2017 - Jul. 2017

AuthenMetric Beijing, China

• Developed real-time and time-coherent portrait segmentation algorithms on mobile devices.

Sep. 2017 - May. 2021 *Los Angeles, CA*

University of Southern California

- Conducted research on interpretable deep neural networks with feed-forward design that was awarded JVCI 2021 Best Paper Award.
- Proposed a pioneering framework that insinuates the idea of adversarial learning with human robot interaction that hits USC headline and IROS 2019 Best Paper Finalist.
- Conducted research and engineering on interactive high-resolution portrait manipulation using generative adversarial networks (GANs).

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

NeurIPS 2022. Changyou chen, Jianyi Zhang, Yi Xu, Liqun Chen, Jiali Duan, Yiran Chen, Son Tran, Belinda Zeng, Trishul Chilimbi. "Why do We Need Large Batchsizes in Contrastive Learning? A Gradient-Bias Perspective".

CVPR 2022. Jiali Duan*, Liqun Chen*, Son Tran, Jinyu Yang, Yi Xu, Zeng Belinda, Trishul Chilimbi. "Multimodal Alignment using Representation Codebook"

CVPR 2022. Jinyu Yang, **Jiali Duan**, Son Tran, Liqun Chen, Yi Xu, Zeng Belinda, Trishul Chilimbi. "Multi-modal Representation Learning with Triple Contrastive Learning"

ICPR 2022. Xiaoyuan Guo*, **Jiali Duan***, C.-C. Jay Kuo, Judy Gichoya, Imon Banerjee. "Augmenting Vision Language Pretraining by Learning Codebook with Visual Semantics"

ICMR 2022. Xiaoyuan Guo, **Jiali Duan**, Saptarshi Purkayastha, Hari Trivedi, Judy Gichoya, Imon Banejee. "OSCARS: An Outlier-Sensitive Content-Based Radiography Retrieval System".

CVPR 2021. Jiali Duan, Yen-Liang Lin, Son Tran, Larry Davis, C.-C. Jay Kuo. "SLADE: A Self-Training Framework for Distance Metric Learning".

SCMLS 2020. Jiali Duan, Xiaoyuan Guo, Son Tran, C.-C. Jay Kuo. "Fashion Compatibility Recommendation via Unsupervised Metric Graph Learning".

IROS 2019. **Jiali Duan***, Qian Wang*, Lerrel Pinto, C.-C. Jay Kuo, Stefanos Nikolaidis. "Robot Learning via Human Adversarial Games".

JVCI 2018. C.-C. Jay Kuo, Min Zhang, Siyang Li, **Jiali Duan**, Yueru Chen. Interpretable Convolutional Neural Networks via Feedforward Design.

ACM-TOMM 2017. **Jiali Duan**, Shuai Zhou, Jun Wan, Xiaoyuan Guo, Stan Z.Li. A Unified Framework for Multi-Modal Isolated Gesture Recognition.

ACCVW 2016. Jiali Duan, Jiali Duan, Shengcai Liao, Xiaoyuan Guo, Stan Z. Li. Face Detection by Aggregating Visible Components.

CCBR 2016. Jiali Duan, Shengcai Liao, Shuai Zhou, Stan Z. Li. Face Classification, A Specialized Benchmark Study.

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

- Associate Journal Editor for APSIPA
- Reviewer for CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICML, NeurIPS, ACL, EMNLP, TOMM, RA-L, ICIP
- Volunteer for USC Robotics Open House in 2019

AWARDS

- Best Paper Award in the 2021 Journal of Visual Communication and Image Processing.
- Best Paper Award in the 2019 International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems.
- Best Student Paper Award for CCBR 2016.